A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Board of Physical Therapy, 2016-2021.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Board of Physical Therapy,
2016-2021.
The Library of Virginia
53865
Virginia. Dept. of Health Professions.
1.05 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions
Acquisition Information
Accession 53865 was transferred by the Dept. of Health Professions on 04/13/2023.
Historical Information
Regulation of the health professions began late in the nineteenth century. On January 31, 1884, the General Assembly passed an act creating the Board of Medical Examiners to certify physicians for practice in Virginia. Two years later, acts establishing the Board of Dental Examiners (now the Board of Dentistry) and the Board of Pharmacy were passed by the General Assembly on February 26 and March 3, 1886, respectively. The Board of Embalmers (now the Board of Funeral Directors and Embalmers) was created by an act passed on March 5, 1894, and the Board of Veterinary Examiners (now the Board of Veterinary Medicine) was established by an act passed on February 27, 1896. On May 1, 1903, the General Assembly created the Board of Graduate Nurses (now the State Board of Nursing), and on March 11, 1916, the Board of Optometry was established by legislative action.
The Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards was created by an act passed by the General Assembly on March 31, 1977, to provide administrative services to the health regulatory boards of the state. The boards continue to regulate their professions through the examination, licensing, and disciplining of the practitioners of health science. In 1986, the Dept. of Health Regulatory Boards became the Dept. of Health Professions. Its mission is to enhance the delivery of safe and competent health care by licensing qualified health care professionals, enforcing standards of practice, and providing information to both practitioners and consumers of health care services.
Scope and Content
Official minutes and related attachments documenting the meetings, activities, discussions and policy decisions and recommendations of the Virginia Board of Physical Therapy. Also includes minutes for Committees and other groups (Legislative/Regulatory Committee, Special Conference Committee, Regulatory Advisory Panel), as well as records related to informal fact finding conferences, telephone conferences, and formal administrative hearings.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Board of Physical Therapy, 2016-2021.
  - Accession 53865 (2016-2021).
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2016 Jan 27. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Legislative/Regulatory Committee, 2016 Jan 29. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2016 Feb 9. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Telephone conference, 2016 Mar 3. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Board minutes, 2016 May 10. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Licensure Compact Subcommittee, 2016 Sept 27. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2016 Oct 20. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Licensure Compact Subcommittee, 2016 Oct 25. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Board minutes, 2016 Nov 15. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Public hearing, 2017 Feb 7. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Legislative/Regulatory Committee, 2017 Feb 7. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Licensure Compact Subcommittee, 2017 Feb 7. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Telephone conference, 2017 Feb 21. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Board minutes, 2017 Mar 29. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2017 Mar 29. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2017 May 11. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Legislative/Regulatory Committee, 2017 June 29. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Regulatory Advisory Panel, 2017 June 29. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Board minutes, 2017 Aug 22. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2017 Sept 28. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Public hearing, 2017 Oct 13. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Regulatory Advisory Panel, 2017 Nov 15. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Board minutes, 2017 Nov 17. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Feb 13. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Formal administrative hearing, 2018 Feb 13. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Telephone conference, 2018 Mar 2. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Legislative/Regulatory Committee, 2018 Apr 10. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Board minutes, 2018 May 1. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 June 19. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 Aug 16. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Aug 16. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Board minutes, 2018 Nov 13. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2018 Nov 13. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Telephone conference, 2018 Dec 4. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2019 Jan 14. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Legislative/Regulatory Committee, 2019 Feb 11. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Board minutes, 2019 Feb 19. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2019 Feb 19. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Informal fact finding conference, 2019 Mar 25. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Board meeting, 2019 May 16. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Public hearing, 2019 June 27. (Box 2, Folder 20)